Guide to the William Ward Watkin Papers, 1903-1956 MS 352
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
William Ward Watkin papers
1903-1956
bulk
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Watkin, William Ward
MS 352
5.5 Linear Feet (11 boxes + oversize materials in map drawer 28)
The papers detail the academic and architectural career of William Ward Watkin. Included in the collection are personal information, business correspondence, construction photographs and architectural drawings of the early Rice Institute, and drawings of projects from his private architectural career.
Biographical Note
William Ward Watkin was born in Boston, Massachusetts, on January 21, 1886. His parents were Fred W. Watkin and Mary Hancock Watkin. Watkin grew up in Pennsylvania, the home state of his mother's family. He graduated from Danville High School in 1903 and entered the University of Pennsylvania, pursuing the study of architecture under Paul Phillipe Cret. Following his graduation in 1908, Watkin spent one year traveling in Europe, principally in England.
Upon his return from Europe, Watkin joined the Boston office of Cram, Goodhue and Ferguson, then one of the most prominent architectural firms in the United States. At the time of Watkin's employment, 1909, Cram, Goodhue and Ferguson had received the commission to produce a campus plan and to design the initial buildings of the Rice Institute in Houston, Texas. Watkin worked on the development of both the campus plan and the building plan in the office; when construction was to begin, in the summer of 1910, Watkin was sent to Houston to serve as Cram, Goodhue and Ferguson's representative supervisor. In this capacity Watkin not only oversaw the construction of the initial Institute group--the Administration Building, the Mechanical laboratory and Powerhouse, and the North and South residence halls - but most of the Institute's subsequent development: the Physics laboratory (1913-1915), east Hall (1913-1914), West Hall (1915-1916), three proposed President's houses (1913, 1915, 1923-1924), the Field House (1920), the Chemistry Laboratory (1923-1925), a proposed Alumni Hall (1927), two proposed libraries (1927, 1940-1941), and the Founder's Statue (1927-1930). Watkin himself was to design the Faculty Club - Cohen House (1927), Rice Stadium (1938), and the Naval ROTC building (1941). He also served as consulting architect to Staub and Rather in the design and construction of the Fondren Library (1946-1949), M.D. Anderson Hall (1946-1947), and the Abercrombie Laboratory (1947-1948).
As supervising architect, Watkin worked closely with Dr. Edgar Odell Lovett, president of the Rice Institute. Lovett offered Watkin a faculty appointment and the Institute opened in the fall of 1912 with Watkin as instructor in architectural engineering. In the summer of 1916 he was made an assistant professor and in 1922 he became a full professor. In 1914 the architecture faculty expanded to two, and to three in 1915. Rice awarded the first professional degrees in architecture in 1917. Watkin's efforts to provide his students with a thorough course in architectural studies led him to organize a traveling fellowship in 1928. Watkin's academic duties were not restricted to the Architecture department. He was also Curator of Grounds, Chairman of the Faculty Committee on Buildings and Grounds, and Chairman of the Faculty Committee on Outdoor Sports, a position which resulted in his serving a term as president of the Southwest Conference in 1920. At the time of his sabbatical in the 1928-1929 academic year, Watkin resigned the athletic committee post. He remained, however, head of Buildings and Grounds, as his resignation of this post was not accepted by Dr. Lovett. During World War II, Watkin chaired the Committee on Air Raid protection and Civilian defense.
As early as 1912 Watkin was accepting independent architectural commissions. Between 1913 and 1915 he entered into partnership with George Endress of Austin, practicing under the name Endress and Watkin. This firm was dissolved at the end of 1919 and Watkin thereafter practiced under his own name. Also in 1919 Watkin ceased his affiliation with Cram, Goodhue and Ferguson, though he continued to operate, on a commission basis, as supervisor for their Texas projects. In addition to practicing architecture, Watkin consulted on projects, and in 1933 he was appointed to the Board of Architectural Consultants, an advisory group connected with the design of the Federal Triangle in Washington, D.C.
During the teens and twenties, Watkin wrote articles for journals, primarily dealing with Houston, its growth and development, and the implications these held for the city's architecture. Watkin contributed descriptive pieces on the Rice Institute to Progressive Houston and the Southern Architectural Review, Houston's short-lived architectural magazine. Not until the late twenties did he become more involved in research and writing. In 1930 the Rice Institute Pamphlet published a series of lectures Watkin had given on the new architecture in Europe; Pencil Points reprinted these in 1931. Watkin wrote two additional essays for Pencil Points one published in 1931 on new directions in ecclesiastical architecture, and another in 1932. This former essay was something of a prolegomena to Watkin's first book, "The Church of Tomorrow" published in 1936. In 1951 Watkin's second book, "Planning and Building the Modern Church," was published. At the time of his death he was planning to write a book on architecture in Texas.
Watkin had numerous academic and professional associations. He was a member of the Houston Philosophical Society, the Texas Philosophical Society and the Houston Country Club. Watkin was a charter member of the Rice Institute Faculty Club. He had become a member of the American Institute of Architects in 1913, and was elected to the College of Fellows in 1949. Watkin was a communicant of Trinity Church.
William Ward Watkin died on June 24, 1952 from complications following surgery for a broken kneecap. He was survived by his wife, Josephine Cockrell Watkin, whom he had married in 1933. Watkin had previously been married to Annie Ray Townsend Watkin, who died in 1929. Their three children were Annie Ray Watkin Biehl Hoagland, Rosemary Watkin Barrick, and William Ward Watkin, Jr.
Excerpted from Stephen Fox's 1976 unpublished "Guide to the Papers of William Ward Watkin in the Woodson Research Center of the Rice University."
Scope and Contents
The William Ward Watkin Papers, totaling 13 document boxes, detail the academic and architectural career of Watkin. The papers include correspondence, newspaper clippings, photographs and architectural drawings gathered by Annie Ray Watkin from her father's papers. The collection is arranged in three series.
The Biographical series concentrates on Watkin's personal life. It includes materials from his school days, family correspondence, speeches, lectures and writings. The speeches and writings are architectural in subject.
The series Architectural Career covers both Watkin's time at Rice and his private practice. Watkin first came to Rice in 1910, as an employee of the architecture firm Cram, Goodhue and Ferguson. He oversaw the construction of the Administration Building, the Mechanical Laboratory and Power Plant, and a Residential Group, the first buildings on the campus. Then, Watkin went on to design and supervise the building of other structures on campus. Most of the materials in the sub-series, Rice Institute, are photographic but there are some textual materials. The sub-series Private Practice incorporates many projects Watkin undertook outside of his career at Rice. These papers include correspondence with clients and drawings of projects.
The final series Academic Career touches upon the various roles Watkin played at Rice, other than as architect. Most prominent are records from his time with the Architecture department.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored onsite at the Woodson Research Center.
Acquisition Information
The papers were gifted by Ray Watkin Strange and the Watkin family from the early 1970s through the early 2000s.
General note
Portions of this collection are available online at https://scholarship.rice.edu/handle/1911/12394.
Note to researchers: Much of the correspondence is photocopied. The originals are in the possession of the Watkin heirs.
Related Material
Edgar Odell Lovett Presidential Papers for additional correspondence and information on the building of Rice and Rice Academics.
University Archives - Architectural Files for drawings and blueprints of Rice buildings.
MS 465, the Ray Watkin Hoagland Papers for additional information about William Ward Watkin.
Index Terms
Subjects
Faculty; Universities and colleges; College buildings -- Texas; Architects -- Texas; Architecture
Places
Texas -- Houston
Subjects (Persons)
Watkin, William Ward; Lovett, Edgar Odell; Watkin, William Ward; Cram, Ralph Adams
Subjects (Corporations)
Cram, Goodhue, and Ferguson; Rice University
- Series I. Biographical, 1903-1953.; 10 linear inches.
  Scope and Contents note
  Arranged in seven sub-series - Personal, Family, Correspondence, Financial Information, Memberships, Speaking Engagements, Writings. This series includes a variety of personal information about Watkin from college days to family vacations. The Writings sub-series includes articles, lectures, and reviews of Watkin's books.
  - Subseries A: Personal
    - High School Award, Business Card (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Sketchbook - History of Renaissance Architecture, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - William Ward Watkin Photographs, 1909, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Anniversary of Cram and Ferguson, Boston, c.1909 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Resume, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Sketches of William Ward Watkin, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Certificates and Awards, 1937, 1938, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Clippings about William Ward Watkin and Rice Institute, 1916, 1923, 1933, 1936, 1938, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - William Ward Watkin and Second Wife Josephine - Photographs, 1933, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Christmas Cards Designed by William Ward Watkin, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - William Ward Watkin's death, 1952-1953 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Subseries B: Family
    - Annie Ray Watkin (William Ward Watkin's First Wife), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Annie Ray Watkin's Death, March 1929 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Birth of Daughter Annie Ray, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - William Ward Watkin, Jr. and Wife, 1942, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Family Trip to Europe, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Family Trips, 1915, 1916, 1921, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - European Trips, 1920's - 1930's Photographs of Architectural Features, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - European Trips, 1925-1928
    - Postcards
      - Aqueduct (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - Bridges and Archways (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - Castles (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Church Doorways (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - Church - Exteriors (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - Church - Interiors (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - Colleges (Oxford) (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - Columns (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - Fountains (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - Hotels (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - Monuments (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - Mosaics (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - Public Buildings (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - Railway Station (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - Restaurants (Box 1, Folder 33)
      - Stadium (Box 1, Folder 34)
      - Stairways (Box 1, Folder 35)
      - Streets and Villages (Box 1, Folder 36)
      - Towers (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Subseries C: Correspondence
    - John Angel
      - 1935-1936, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Christmas Cards
      - 1933-1937, 1939, 1941-1943 (Box 1, Folder 39)
      - 1944-1959 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Ralph A. Cram, 1921, 1925, 1935, 1938, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Fellow Architects, 1912-1913, 1915, 1933, 1943, 1949, 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Clubs - University Club and Houston Country Club, 1918, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Mary M. Watkin (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - General, 1910, 1912, 1916, 1918, 1920, 1925, 1936, 1938, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Regarding The Church of Tomorrow, 1933-1934, 1936-1938, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Regarding Planning and Building the Modern Church, 1951-1952, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Subseries D: Financial Information
    - Donation to Trinity Church (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Lassig Limestone Quarry Corporation (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous, 1925-1926 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Royalties on Planning and Building the Modern Church, 1954-1956 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Subseries E: Memberships
    - American Institute of Architects, 1910, 1912-1913, 1920, 1936, 1948-1949 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Philosophical Society of Texas, 1941, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Subseries F: Speaking Engagements
    - 1913-1916, 1918, 1930, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Subseries G: Writings
    - Articles
      - A Bit of Rice Institute Contemporary History Prepared for the Annual Industrial Edition of the Houston Post, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - Architectural Traditions Appearing in the Earlier Buildings of the Rice Institute, July, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - Architecture In Texas, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - Are We Making Progress in Our Church Architecture?, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - Art at Christmastide, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - Art, Culture, and the Community, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - The Centennial of an Independent Frontier, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - The College Buildings, December, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - For the Future, Fitness and Harmony, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      - Impressions of Modern Architecture parts 1,2,3, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - In Memoriam - Ralph Adams Cram, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - Make No Little Plans, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 24)
      - The Maturing Beauty of the National Capital, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - The Middle Ages: The Approach to the Truce Of God, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 26)
      - Modern Architecture, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 27)
      - Notes on Houston, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 28)
      - Plans for the Rice Institute, 1912? (Box 2, Folder 29)
      - The Search for a Direct Manner of Expression in Design The New Manner in France and Northern Europe The Advent of the New Manner in America, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 30)
      - Article for Southern Architectural Review, 1910 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      - Texas Technological College, Lubbock, Texas, 1928-1929 (Box 2, Folder 32)
      - Twenty-fifth Anniversary, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 33)
      - Whence Comes this Modernism?, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Editorials
      - Houston in Retrospect, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Lectures
      - Architectural Traditions Appearing in the Earlier Buildings of the Rice Institute, c. 1950 (Box 2, Folder 36)
      - Notes on Building Appraisal, c.1918? (Box 2, Folder 37)
      - Ralph Adams Cram., c.1941? (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Radio
      - Architecture, November 14, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Reviews of Books
      - The Church of Tomorrow, 1936-1937 (Box 2, Folder 40)
      - Planning and Building the Modern Church, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Series II. Architectural Career, 1910-1952; 24 linear inches.
  Arranged in two sub-series - Rice Institute and Private Practice. This series includes correspondence and drawings (some oversized) about many architectural projects Watkin supervised and designed.
  - Subseries A: Rice Institute
    - Buildings
      - Campanile, Mechanical Laboratory and Power House, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 42)
      - Chemistry Laboratory, 1923-19 (Box 2, Folder 43)
      - Cohen House (Box 2, Folder 44)
      - Engineering Quadrangle (Box 2, Folder 45)
      - Field House and Grandstands, 1920-19 (Box 2, Folder 46)
      - Fondren Library and Anderson Hall, 1945, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 47)
      - Physics Laboratory, 1914, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 48)
      - President's House, 1912, 1915, 1923 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Residential Group (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - William Marsh Rice Statue (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Stadium, 1938-19 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Rice Institute Brochures, 1912-19, 1914-19, 1940, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Articles re: Construction (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Financial
      - Accounting Pages
        - 1912-19 (Box 3, Folder 7)
        - 1913-19 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Construction Estimates (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - Equipment Inspections, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Reports and General Correspondence
      - Construction, 1910-19 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Edgar O. Lovett, 1921, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - Construction Reports (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - Administration Building construction (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Photographs, Pre-construction
      - Flood, April 16, 1912 (Box 3b, Folder 1)
    - Photographs, Construction
      - Campus, February 10, 1913 (Box 3b, Folder 2)
      - Drains and Sewers, 1912 (Box 3b, Folder 3)
      - Flood, 1911 (Box 3b, Folder 4)
      - Tunnel Views (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Tunnels, 1911-1912 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Administration Building
        - Numbered Construction Photographs
          - I/1 - 45 (Box 4, Folder 3)
          - I/46 - 92 (Box 4, Folder 4)
          - II/4 - 70 (Box 4, Folder 5)
        - Unnumbered Construction Photographs, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Setting Cornerstones (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - General Campus
        - Numbered Construction Views (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - Mechanical Lab/Power Plant/Campanile
        - Numbered Construction Photographs
          - I/12 - 100 (Box 4, Folder 9)
          - II/1-63 (Box 4, Folder 10)
        - Unnumbered Construction Photographs, 1911 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Physics Laboratories, 1913-1914
        - Numbered Construction Views
          - II/1-49 (Box 5, Folder 2)
          - III/50-92 (Box 5, Folder 3)
        - Unnumbered Construction Views (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Residential Group
      - Numbered Construction Views
        - East Hall (Baker College), III/23-87, 1913-1914 (Box 5, Folder 5)
        - South Hall, II/25-66, 1911-1912 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Unnumbered Construction Views
        - 1912 (Box 5, Folder 7)
        - 1916 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Photographs, Post-Construction
      - Campus Site, 1913 (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - East Entrance Road and Gate, 1912 (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - Forecourt in Front of Administration Building, 1912, 1913, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 11)
      - Main Entrance Court, 1912, 1913, ca.1938, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 12)
      - Quadrangle, Before 1915, After 1915, After 1930 (Box 5, Folder 13)
      - Rear of Residential Hall, 1912 (Box 5, Folder 14)
      - Abercrombie Laboratory, c. 1949 (Box 5, Folder 15)
      - Administration Building (Lovett)
        - Exterior, 1912-19, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 16)
        - Interior, President's Office, n.d (Box 5, Folder 17)
        - View of Administration From Dormitories, n.d (Box 5, Folder 18)
        - Bas-relief, n.d (Box 5, Folder 19)
      - Administration, Physics, Campanile, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 20)
      - Aerial
        - postcard, ca.1916, n.d, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 21)
        - 193? (Box 5, Folder 22)
      - Athletic Field, 1913 (Box 6a, Folder 1)
      - Chemistry Laboratory Rendering, ca.1923, n.d. (Box 6a, Folder 2)
      - Cohen House, Laying of Cornerstone, 1927 (Box 6a, Folder 3)
      - Cohen House, ca.1927, 1935 (Box 6a, Folder 4)
      - Field House, n.d. (Box 6a, Folder 5)
      - Fondren Library, ca.1949 (Box 6a, Folder 6)
      - Harris Bayou, 1913 (Box 6a, Folder 7)
      - Mechanical Laboratory/Power Plant/Campanile, 1912, n.d. (Box 6a, Folder 8)
      - Physics Laboratory, ca.1914, n.d. (Box 6a, Folder 9)
      - Residential Group
        - Exterior, ca.1910-1912, n.d. (Box 6a, Folder 10)
        - Interior, ca.1912 (Box 6a, Folder 11)
      - William Marsh Rice Statue, n.d. (Box 6a, Folder 12)
      - Stadium, ca. 1938 (Box 6a, Folder 13)
      - Trees (Box 6a, Folder 14)
  - Subseries B: Private Practice
    - Brochure of the Work of William Ward Watkin, Architect (Box 6a, Folder 15)
    - Booklet, Various Buildings, 1939-1940 (Box 6a, Folder 16)
    - Consultation - Texas Medical Center, 1944 (Box 6a, Folder 17)
    - Board of Architectural Consultants, 1933, 1934 (Box 6a, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence
      - Cram and Ferguson, Architects, 1919, 1920 (Box 6a, Folder 19)
      - Inner-office Correspondence - Work Reports, 1925 (Box 6a, Folder 20)
      - Miscellaneous Projects, 1913-1920 (Box 6a, Folder 21)
      - Miscellaneous Projects, 1922-1929, 1943 (Box 6a, Folder 22)
      - Possible Projects
        - St. Michael and All Angels, 1952, 1954 (Box 6a, Folder 23)
        - J.S. Cullinan House, 1915-1916 (Box 6a, Folder 24)
    - Projects
      - Courtland Place, 1912 (Box 6, Folder 25)
      - J.M. Bennett House, San Antonio, TX, 1914 (Box 6a, Folder 26)
      - William Ward Watkin House, Houston, TX, 1915 (Box 6a, Folder 27)
      - Nicholson House, 1916 (Box 6a, Folder 28)
      - Priddie House, Beaumont, TX, 1916 (Box 6a, Folder 29)
      - Trinity Church, Houston, TX, 1917-1920 (Box 6, Folder 30)
      - Sul Ross College, Alpine, TX, 1919 (Box 6a, Folder 31)
      - Carter Family cemetery monument, 1920s (Box 6a, Folder 31a)
      - Palmer Bradley House, 1920 (Box 6a, Folder 32)
      - Harry Wiess House, 1920 (Box 6a, Folder 33)
      - Miller Memorial Theater, Hermann Park, Houston, TX, 1921 (Box 6a, Folder 34)
      - Autry House, Houston, TX, 1921-1922 (Box 6a, Folder 35)
      - Harry B. Weiser House, Houston, TX, 1922 (Box 6a, Folder 36)
      - Museum of Fine Arts, Houston, TX, 1922-1926 (Box 6a, Folder 37)
      - E.M. Gruendler House, Houston, TX, 1923 (Box 6a, Folder 38)
      - Neil T. Masterson House, Houston, TX, 1923-1924 (Box 6a, Folder 39)
      - Houston Public Library, Houston, TX, 1923-1925 (Box 6b, Folder 40)
      - YWCA, Galveston, TX, 1923-1925 (Box 6, Folder 41)
      - E.M. Armstrong House, Houston, TX, 1924 (Box 6b, Folder 42)
      - John V. Scott House, Houston, TX, 1924 (Box 6b, Folder 43)
      - Texas Tech College, Lubbock, TX, 1924-1925 (Box 6b, Folder 44)
      - Consultant for Houston School Board, 1924-1928 (Box 6b, Folder 45)
      - B.B. Gilmer House, Houston, TX, 1925 (Box 6b, Folder 46)
      - Kinkaid School, Houston, TX, 1925 (Box 6b, Folder 47)
      - E.L. Crain House, 1926 (Box 6b, Folder 48)
      - W.T. Eldridge House, Sugarland, TX, 1926 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - F.A. Heitman House, Houston, TX, 1926-1927 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Alphabet Realty Company, Specifications, 1927 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Howard Hughes Family Memorial Monument, 1927 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Palmer Chapel, Houston, TX, 1927 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - College of Industrial Arts, Denton, TX, 1927-1928 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - MacGregor Park, 1933-1936 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - Cohen Memorial, Galveston, TX, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - James Bowie Memorial, Texarkana, TX, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 9)
      - Lt. Richard Dowling Memorial, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 10)
      - Christ Church Chancel, 1938-1939 (Box 7, Folder 11)
      - Central Church of Christ, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 12)
      - Kinkaid School, Houston, TX, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 13)
      - St. Mark's Church, Beaumont, TX, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 14)
      - First Church of Christ Scientist, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 15)
      - Methodist Hospital, Houston, TX, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 16)
      - Cleveland Sewall House (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Subseries C: Oversize materials (Drawer 28)
- Series III. Academic Career, 1914-1949; 10 linear inches.